1 And the second lot came out for Simeon, namely for the tribe of the children of Simeon according to their families. And their inheritance was in the midst of the inheritance of the children of Judah.
2 And they had in their inheritance: Beersheba which is Sheba, and Moladah. 
3 And Hazar-shual, and Balah, and Ezem. 
4 And Eltolad, and Bethul, and Hormah. 
5 And Ziklag, and Beth marcaboth, and Hazar-susah. 
6 And Beth-lebaoth, and Sharuhen. Thirteen cities with their villages. 
7 And Ain, and Rimmon, and Ether, and Ashan: Four cities with their villages. 
8 And all the villages that were around these cities, to Baalath-beer, which is Ramah southward. This is the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Simeon according to their families. 
9 The inheritance of the children of Simeon was taken from the portion of the children of Judah. For the portion of the children of Judah was too much for them, and therefore it is out of their inheritance that an inheritance had been given to the children of Simeon.
10 The third lot fell for the children of Zebulun according to their families. And the coasts of their inheritance came to Sarid. 
11 And their border extends westward to Maralah, and reaches to Dabbesheth, and meets the river that is before Jokneam.
12 And it turns from Sarid eastward toward the rising sun to the border of Chisloth-tabor, and goes out to Daberath and goes up to Japhia. 
13 And from there it goes along eastward to Gittha-hepher and to Ittha-Kazin, and goes out to Rimmon and turns to Neah. 
14 And this border turns about it on the north side to Hannathon, and its ends are in the valley of Iphtah-el.
15 Inside this border were the cities Kattath, and Nahallal, and Shimron, and Idalah, and Bethlehem. Twelve cities and their villages.
16 This is the inheritance of the children of Zebulun according to their families, namely these cities and their villages. 
17 The fourth lot came out for Issachar, namely the children of Issachar according to their families. 
18 And their border was Jezreel, and Chesulloth, and Shunem. 
19 And Hapharaim, and Shion, and Anaharath. 
20 And Rabbith, and Kishion, and Ebez. 
21 And Remeth, and Engannim, and En-haddah, and Beth-pazzez. 
22 And this coast extends to Tabor, and Shahazumah, and Beth-shemesh. And the ends of their border reaches the Jordan. Sixteen cities with their villages.
23 This is the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Issachar according to their families, namely the cities and their villages.
24 And the fifth lot came out for the tribe of the children of Asher according to their families.
25 And their coast was Helkath, and Hali, and Beten, and Achshaph. 
26 And Allammelech, and Amad, and Mishal, and came to Carmel westward, and to Shihor-libnath.
27 And it turns toward the rising sun to Beth-dagon, and came to Zebulun and to the valley of Iphtah-el, to the north of Beth-emek and Neiel, and goes out on the left side of Cabul.
28 And to Ebron, and Rehob, and Hammon, and Kanah, and to great Sidon. 
29 Then the coast turns to Ramah and to the fortified city of Tyre. And this border turns to Hosah, and its ends are at the sea from Hebel to Achzib.
30 And their territory contains Ummah, and Aphek, and Rehob. Twenty two cities with their villages.
31 This is the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Asher according to their families, namely these cities and their villages. 
32 The sixth lot came out for the children of Naphtali, namely for the children of Naphtali according to their families. 
33 Their coast was from Heleph, and from Allon in Zaanannim, and Adaminekeb, and Jabneel, to Lakkum. And its ends are at the Jordan.
34 And this coast turns westward to Aznoth-tabor, and from there it extends to Hukkok and reaches Zebulun on the south, and reaches Asher on the west, and reaches Judah by the Jordan toward the rising sun.
35 And the fortified cities are Ziddim, and Zer, and Hammath, and Rakkath, and Chinnereth. 
36 And Adamah, and Ramah, and Hazor. 
37 And Kedesh, and Edrei, and En-hazor. 
38 And Iron, and Migdal-el, and Horem, and Beth-anath, and Beth-shemesh. Nineteen cities with their villages. 
39 This is the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Naphtali according to their families, namely the cities and their villages. 
40 The seventh lot came out for the tribe of the children of Dan according to their families.
41 And the coast of their inheritance was Zorah, and Eshtaol, and Ir-Shemesh. 
42 And Shaalabbin, and Aijalon, and Ithlah. 
43 And Elon, and Timnah, and Ekron. 
44 And Eltekeh, and Gibbethon, and Baalath. 
45 And Jehud, and Bene-berak, and Gath-rimmon. 
46 And Me-jarkon, and Rakkon, with the territory opposite Joppa. 
47 But the coasts of the children of Dan were too small for them. Therefore the children of Dan went up to fight against Leshem. And they took it, and smote it with the edge of the sword, and possessed it, and dwelt there, And they gave the name Dan to Leshem, after the name of Dan their father.
48 This is the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Dan according to their families, namely these cities and their villages. 
49 When they had finished dividing the land according to its borders, then the children of Israel gave to Joshua the son of Nun a possession among them.
50 According to the word of Yahweh, they gave him the city that he asked namely Timnath-serah on the mount Ephraim. And he built the city and dwelt there. 
51 These are the inheritances, which was distributed by lot before Yahweh in Shiloh at the door of the tent of meeting, by Eleazar the priest and Joshua the son of Nun and the chief fathers of the tribes of the children of Israel.
