1 And he made an altar of brass which was twenty cubits in length, and twenty cubits in width, and ten cubits high. 
2 And he made a molten container that was called the sea. It was ten cubits in diameter from brim to brim, and a round shape on each part, and five cubits high, and its circumference was the length of a cord of thirty cubits. 
3 And there were the likenesses of knops under [the brim] all around, ten per cubit, all around the sea. And the two rows of knops were melted with the container into a single piece.
4 And the container stood on twelve oxen among which three were looking toward the north, and three were looking toward the west, and three were looking toward south, and three were looking toward the east. And the container stood above them, and all the oxen were looking out of the container, and their hindquarters were inward. 
5 And the thickness of the container was a handbreadth, and its brim was like the work of the brim of a cup with flowers of lilies. It contained two thousand baths. 
6 And he made ten basins, and placed five on the right side of the temple, and five on the left. They were to be used to wash the various parts of burnt offerings, and the sea was only for the washing of the bodies of priests. 
7 And he made ten candlesticks of gold according to the ordinance concerning them. And he placed them in the temple, five on the right side and five on the left. 
8 And he made ten tables and placed them in the temple, five on the right side and five on the left. And he made one hundred bowls of gold. 
9 And he made the courtyard for the priests, and also the great courtyard with its doors, and he overlaid these doors with brass. 
10 And he placed the sea on the right side of the temple in the southeast. 
11 And Huram made the pots, and the shovels, and the cauldrons. So Huram finished the work that he made for king Solomon, for the house of God. 
12 He had made the two pillars, with the two capitals and their bowls on the top of the pillars, and the two lattices to cover the two bowls of the capitals that were on the top of the pillars. 
13 And four hundred pomegranates [of brass] for the two lattices, two rows of pomegranates per lattice to cover the two bowls of the capitals that were on the top of the pillars. 
14 And he made also bases, and the basins on the bases. 
15 And the sea, and twelve bulls under it. 
16 And the pots, and the shovels, and the flesh-hooks. All these utensils that king Solomon caused Huram Abi to make for the house of Yahweh were of burnished brass.
17 The king melted them [he ordered them to be melted] in the plain of the Jordan, in clayey ground between Succoth and Zeredah. 
18 And Solomon made all these utensils in great quantity, because the weight of the available brass could not be measured. 
19 And Solomon made all the other utensils of the house of God, and the golden altar also, and the golden tables on which the shewbread was placed. 
20 And the candlesticks with their lamps, of pure gold, to light according to the ordinance before the oracle. 
21 And the flowers, and the lamps, and the tongs, all of gold, of pure gold. 
22 And the snuffers, and the bowls, and the spoons, and the censers, all of pure gold. And the doors of the holy place of the house, and the doors within the house at the entrance of the most holy place, they were made of gold.
