1 And Moses answered and said, Behold they will not believe me and they will not listen to my voice. For they will say, Yahweh has not appeared to you. 
2 And Yahweh said to him, What is in your hand. And he answered, A rod. 
3 And God said, Throw it to the ground. And he threw it to the ground, and it became a snake. And Moses backed away from it. 
4 And Yahweh said to Moses, Stretch out your hand and take hold of it by the tail. And he stretched out his hand and took hold of it, and the serpent became a rod in his hand. 
5 And God said, this is what you will do and they will believe that Yahweh the God of their fathers, the God of Abraham and the God of Isaac and the God of Jacob, has appeared to you. 
6 And Yahweh said to him, Put your hand in your bosom. And he put his hand in his bosom, then he withdrew it and behold, his hand was covered with leprosy as white as snow. 
7 And God said, Put your hand back into your bosom. And he put his hand back into his bosom, then he withdrew it and behold, it was again like his other flesh. 
8 And God said, If they do not believe you and do not listen to the voice of the first sign, then they will believe the voice of the second sign. 
9 And If they do not believe even these two signs and do not listen to your voice, then you will take water from the river and you will pour it on the dry ground. And the water that you take from the river will become blood on the dry ground. 
10 And Moses said to Yahweh: Oh my Lord, I am not eloquent. I have never been a eloquent, not even since you have spoken to your servant. For my mouth and my tongue are embarrassed. 
11 And Yahweh said to him: Who made the mouth of man. Who is he who makes mute or deaf, and who gives sight or makes blind. Is it not I Yahweh. 
12 Go now, and I will be with your mouth and teach you what you will say. 
13 And Moses said, Oh my Lord I pray you, send whoever you want. 
14 And the anger of Yahweh was kindled against Moses. And he said: Is not Aaron the Levite your brother. And I know that he will speak easily. Behold he is coming to meet you. And when he sees you, he will rejoice in his heart. 
15 You will speak to him, and you will put the words into his mouth. And I will be with your mouth and with his mouth, and I will teach you what you have to do. 
16 And he will be your spokesperson to the people. He will be your mouth, and you will be like God to him. 
17 Take this rod in your hand, with which you will make the signs. 
18 And Moses went and returned to Jethro his father in law. And Moses said to him, Please let me go to my brothers who are in Egypt, and see if they are still alive. And Jethro said to Moses, Go in peace. 
19 And Yahweh said to Moses in Midian, Go and return to Egypt. For all those who wanted your life are dead. 
20 And Moses took his wife and his sons and put them on a donkey. And Moses took the rod of God in his hand, and he returned to the land of Egypt. 
21 And Yahweh said to Moses, When you are in Egypt you will perform before Pharaoh all the wonders that I have put in your hands. But I will harden his heart and he will not let the people go. 
22 And you will say to Pharaoh: Thus says Yahweh, Israel is my son, my firstborn. 
23 And I say to you, Let my son go so that he may serve me. If you refuse to let him go, behold I will kill your son, your firstborn. 
24 During the journey at a place where Moses spent the night, [an angel of] Yahweh attacked him and wanted to kill him. 
25 Then Zipporah took a sharp stone and cut off the foreskin of her son, and cast it at the feet of Moses and said: Surely you are for me a husband of blood. 
26 And he [the angel] departed from Moses. Then she said, 'A husband of blood'. It was because of the circumcision. 
27 And Yahweh said to Aaron, Go into the wilderness to meet Moses. And Aaron went and he met Moses at the mountain of God, and kissed him. 
28 And Moses told Aaron all the words of Yahweh who had sent him, and all the signs that he had ordered him to do. 
29 And Moses and Aaron went, and they gathered together all the elders of the children of Israel. 
30 And Aaron reported all the words that Yahweh had spoken to Moses, and he performed the signs in the sight of the people. 
31 And the people believed. They heard that Yahweh had visited the children of Israel, and that he had seen their suffering. Then they bowed down and worshiped.
